Data protection declaration
===========================

Due to its business purpose and its projects and companies, The Reach Group GmbH deals extensively with the collection, processing and use of personal data. Personal data is information about personal or factual circumstances of a certain or identifiable natural person (so-called person concerned), such as name, address, age, e-mail address, telephone number or information about certain preferences, inclinations etc..

The collection of such data means obtaining them; processing personal data means storing, modifying, transmitting, blocking and deleting them; use is any use of personal data that does not constitute processing.

Personal data is protected by the EU General Data Protection Regulation and the national regulations of the member states. The Reach Group GmbH observes these regulations and thus respects the right of the individual to his or her personality and to the protection of his or her privacy.

The Reach Group GmbH takes the protection of your data very seriously. For this purpose, and in order to comply with data protection regulations, the following data protection declaration serves:

1\. Personal data
-----------------

The Reach Group does not collect or process any personal data in the case of mere advertising contacts with the user (e.g. by displaying advertisements on a website). Only non-personal data such as information about the server through which the user has accessed the Internet, the browser used and any advertising clicks by the respective user are logged anonymously. This does not create any personal reference.

The Reach Group GmbH also collects and processes personal data via various advertising media or websites. The scope and nature of the data depends on the information that the user enters by filling in the relevant input fields and submitting this information to The Reach Group.

If there is a contractual relationship between The Reach Group GmbH and the Internet user (for example when requesting a newsletter), The Reach Group processes and uses the data collected from the user to fulfil its obligations towards the user, insofar as this is necessary for this purpose. Insofar as The Reach Group GmbH pursues purposes beyond the processing and fulfilment of contractual or similar relationships with the collection, processing and use of data, this only takes place on the basis of an explicit consent given by the user and only to the extent specified by the consent. Such purposes are essentially marketing-oriented and include the use of the data collected for market research, customer acquisition, product information or service development, among other things.

2\. Legal basis
---------------

Your data will be processed on the following legal bases:

*   With regard to data that you provide in forms, etc., with your consent, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) DSGVO
*   in relation to services which you make use of for the execution of a contract with you, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) DSGVO
*   otherwise, in particular for statistical data and online identifiers, on the basis of legitimate interests, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) DSGVO (see below)

3\. Justified interests
-----------------------

When processing your data, we pursue the following legitimate interests:

*   Improvement of our offer
*   Protection against misuse
*   statistics

4\. Data sources
----------------

Unless otherwise stated, we receive the data from you (including the equipment you use).

5\. Data transmission to third countries
----------------------------------------

Data is transferred to third countries outside the European Union. This is done on the basis of statutory contractual regulations which are intended to ensure an adequate protection of your data and which you can view on request.

6\. Storage time
----------------

We store your data,

*   if you have consented to the processing until you revoke your consent at the most,
*   if we need the data for the execution of a contract, at most as long as the contractual relationship with you exists or legal retention periods run,
*   if we use the data on the basis of a legitimate interest, but only as long as your interest in deletion or anonymization does not predominate.

7\. Purposes
------------

Personal data is only collected by us if and only to the extent and for the purpose for which you voluntarily provide us with the data, e.g. as part of a registration.

We only use and store your personal data within the scope of our services for the following purposes if you have expressly given us your consent:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Domain | Intended use |
| \*.trg.de\* | The Reach Group contact form |
| \*.redintelligence.net\* | Renewed contact in the event of abandonment of purchase funnel |
| \*.abo-angebot.de\*  <br>\*.lesealarm.de\*  <br>\*.aktions-alarm.de\* | Purchase processing |
| \*medialead.de\* | Publisher: Account creation for media lead and commission accounting  <br>End User: Transaction TrackingAdvertiser: Account creation for medialead and partner program management  <br>Account Manager: Account creation for medialead |

8\. Data backup
---------------

The Reach Group GmbH is legally obliged to take the technical and organizational measures necessary to guarantee the protection of personal data, i.e. in particular to protect this data from unauthorized access and processing. All data-processing programs and facilities are password-protected and work using state-of-the-art encryption techniques.

If The Reach Group GmbH uses external servers or service providers to store user data and, where applicable, profile information, The Reach Group GmbH ensures that they are bound by at least the same data protection standards as The Reach Group GmbH itself.

The employees of The Reach Group GmbH are committed to maintaining data secrecy and data protection. This obligation includes, among other things, that employees may only process and use personal data to the extent that this is necessary within the framework of contractual or contract-like relationships or the customer has consented to the use of his data for the respective purposes. Personal data that is no longer required for the fulfilment of contractual purposes by The Reach Group GmbH and/or for the processing and use of which The Reach Group no longer has (or no longer) consent will be destroyed in a way that excludes any misuse.

In order to protect your personal data from unauthorized access by third parties during transmission, we secure the data transmissions, if necessary using SSL encryption. This is a standardized encryption method for online services, especially for the web.

9\. Cookies
-----------

The Reach Group GmbH sometimes use so-called cookies. Cookies do not cause any damage to your computer and do not contain any viruses. Cookies serve to make our website more user-friendly, effective and secure. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and saved by your browser.

Most of the cookies we use are so-called “session cookies”. They are automatically deleted at the end of your visit. Other cookies remain stored on your device until you delete them. These cookies enable us to recognize your browser the next time you visit our website.

You can set your browser so that you are informed about the setting of cookies and only allow cookies in individual cases, exclude the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or generally and activate the automatic deletion of cookies when closing the browser. When cookies are deactivated, the functionality of this website may be limited.

### 9.1 \*reachgroup.com\*

You can object to the collection and storage of data at any time with effect for the future. In order to object to the collection and storage of your visitor data for the future, you can obtain an opt-out cookie under the following link, which means that no visitor data from your browser will be collected and stored in the future: [https://www.trg.de/opt-out](https://www.trg.de/opt-out/)

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| #### Cookie | #### Intended use |
| \_icl\_current\_language | Saves the current language. |
| displayCookieConsent | Saves the consent to the cookie banner so that it is not displayed again after the consent as long as the cookie is valid. |
| PHPSESSID | Identification of the same session by storing an ID. |
| \_ga  <br>\_gid  <br>gatUA-\* | Analysis cookies from Google Analytics. See the section Web Analysis. |

### 9.2 \*redintelligence.net\*

You can object to the collection and storage of data at any time with effect for the future. In order to object to the collection and storage of your visitor data in the future, you can obtain an opt-out cookie under the following link: [https://www.trg.de/opt-out/](https://www.trg.de/opt-out)

Please note that in case of a contradiction you may not be able to use all functions of visited program operator or partner websites to their full extent.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| #### Cookie | #### Intended use |
| uid  <br>rtrgt\_\* | Identify abandoned purchase processes by storing an ID for reactivating the product portfolio already seen. |

### 9.3 \*medialead.de\*

The Reach Group GmbH as operator of medialead takes the protection of your personal data very seriously and strictly adheres to the rules of the applicable data protection laws. Therefore, we hereby inform you about our conscientious handling of your data and for what purpose these data are used by medialead.

The IP address is transmitted with each server request so that the server knows where to send the response. The IP address is given to everyone by an Internet Service Provider (ISP) as soon as they connect to the Internet. We cannot establish any direct personal reference from the information of the IP address. In particular, we cannot conclude on the name, address or other directly identifying data of the user. medialead records the IP address exclusively for reasons of system security and to protect against misuse of our offer.

We store, process and use your data in accordance with the relevant data protection regulations. We use your data, which were raised with conclusion of contract and in the context of the use of the Internet offer, which are necessary for the proper contract fulfilment (among other things in the customer order to be able to participate made available Affiliate programs). Your data will be treated confidentially and will not be passed on to third parties. Any service providers used within the scope of the provision of services or to process your order will only receive the data necessary to fulfil their tasks and, like our own employees, are bound to confidentiality.

If you do not agree to the storage of cookies by medialead, you have the option of simply deleting the cookies or not allowing these cookies to be stored (cookie domain: medialead.de) by making the appropriate setting in your browser.

In order not to be specifically recorded by medialead permanently, you can also object to data storage here (opt-out). The domain medialead.de will then set a counter-cookie in your browser for the exclusion. Please note that your opt-out is no longer technically identifiable to us if you delete the cookies in your browser.

To complete the objection, please click on the following link: [https://medialead.de/privacy-optout.do](https://medialead.de/privacy-optout.do)

Please note that in case of a contradiction you may not be able to use all functions of visited program operator or partner websites to their full extent.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| #### Cookie | #### Intended use |
| session\_trs  <br>trs  <br>trscj | Identification of a purchase process (in one session and across sessions) by storing IDs as part of affiliate marketing. |
| \_icl\_current\_language | Saves the current language. |
| ADM\_CORE  <br>adm  <br>adm\_relogin\_url  <br>PUB\_CORE  <br>ADV\_CORE  <br>adv  <br>PHPSESSID  <br>dev  <br>source | Identification of the same session for the login in medialead by saving IDs. |
| \_ga  <br>\_gid  <br>\_gat\_UA-\* | Analysis cookies from Google Analytics. See the section Web Analysis. |

### 9.4 \*abo-angebot.de\*

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| #### Cookie | #### Intended use |
| PHPSESSID | Identification of the same session by storing an ID. |

### 9.5 \*lesealarm.de\* and \*aktions-alarm.de\*

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| #### Cookie | #### Intended use |
| \_uetsid | Tracking cookie from Microsoft Bing Ads |
| \_ga  <br>\_gid  <br>gat\_UA- | Analysis cookies from Google Analytics. See the section Web Analysis. |

10\. Web analysis
-----------------

We use – like almost every website operator – analysis tools in the form of tracking software to determine the frequency of use and the number of users of our website.

In order to optimize this website and our services, we use Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. “(“Google’). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. However, if IP anonymization is activated on this website, Google will shorten your IP address within Member States of the European Union or in other countries party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area beforehand. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity for the website operator and to provide other services associated with website and Internet use to the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics is not merged with other Google data. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

You can also prevent Google from collecting the data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en. Alternatively, to the browser add-on or within browsers on mobile devices, please click this link to prevent Google Analytics from collecting data on this website in the future (the opt-out only works in this browser and only for this domain). An opt-out cookie is stored on your device. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you must click this link again. For more information, see:

or under

(general information about Google Analytics and data protection).

Please note that the code “gat.\_anonymizeIp();’ has been added to Google Analytics code on this website in order to ensure anonymous collection of IP addresses (so-called IP masking).

11\. Usage-related advertising
------------------------------

The advertising displayed on this website is optimized for you by the anonymous collection and processing of your usage behavior, so that you are shown advertising tailored to your interests. A cookie is stored on your computer for this purpose. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer’s hard drive and enable recognition, but do not allow any personal identification of you. Behavioral targeting is carried out by third-party companies that also advertise websites of other providers. These third-party companies then create the aforementioned user profiles themselves using cookies and use their respective targeting systems to select the collected data for the purpose of user-oriented advertising. These are the following companies:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| EASY Marketing GmbH | Conversion Tracking |
| NEORY GmbH | Ad server and retargeting (If necessary, additional retargeting cookies will be set, which you can view at [http://youronlinechoices.com/uk/](http://youronlinechoices.com/uk/)). |

12\. Social networks
--------------------

### 12.1 Facebook

Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc, 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA and is available at www.facebook.com. The individual social plugins are marked with one of the Facebook logos or the addition ‘Facebook Social Plugin’. A list with the appearance and functions of the individual plugins can be viewed here: developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins. When you visit a page on our website that contains such a social plugin, the browser you use establishes a direct connection to Facebook’s servers. The content of the social plugin is transmitted directly from Facebook to your browser and integrated into the website. We therefore have no control over the amount of data Facebook collects using the social plugins and will therefore inform you to the best of our knowledge: Due to the integration of the social plugins, Facebook is informed that you have visited the corresponding page of our website, even if you are not registered as a Facebook user or are not currently logged in to Facebook. This information, together with your IP address, is transmitted from your browser to a Facebook server in the USA and stored there. According to Facebook information, only an anonymous IP address is stored by non-registered users in Germany. If you are logged in to Facebook, Facebook can directly associate accessing our website with your Facebook account. Facebook receives the information about your visit to our website regardless of whether you interact with the social plugins or not. If you interact with the social plugins, for example by clicking the ‘Like’ button or making a comment, the corresponding information is transmitted directly from your browser to Facebook and stored there. The information is also published on Facebook and displayed to your Facebook friends. The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook as well as your rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy can be found in Facebook’s data protection guidelines, which can be accessed at [www.facebook.com/about/privacy](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy). If you are a registered user of Facebook and do not want Facebook to collect information about you through our website and link to your membership information stored on Facebook, you must log out of Facebook before visiting our website. It is also possible to block the social plugins with add-ons for your browser.

### 12.2 Twitter

This website uses the buttons of the Twitter service provided by Twitter Inc, 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. These plugins can be identified by terms such as “Twitter’ or “Tweet’ or the Twitter logo. Among other things, they make it possible to share a contribution or a page of this website on Twitter. When a user calls up a website containing such a button, his browser establishes a direct connection to Twitter’s servers. The content of the Twitter button is transmitted directly from Twitter to the user’s browser. We therefore have no influence on the amount of data Twitter collects with the help of this plugin and can therefore only inform the user according to our level of knowledge: Afterwards log data such as the user’s IP address, the previously accessed website, etc. are transmitted. For more information, please see Twitter’s privacy policy:

### 12.3 XING

The “XING Share Button’ is used on this website. When you access this website, your browser is used to establish a short-term connection to servers of XING AG, Dammtorstraße 29-32, 20354 Hamburg (“XING”), with which the “XING Share Button” functions (in particular the calculation/display of the counter value) are performed. XING does not store any personal data about you when you access this website. In particular, XING does not store any IP addresses. There is also no evaluation of your usage behavior via the use of cookies in connection with the “XING Share Button’. The latest data protection information on the “XING Share Button’ and additional information can be found on this website:

### 12.4 LinkedIn

This website integrates plugins from LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereinafter referred to as ‘LinkedIn’). You can recognize the LinkedIn plugins by the LinkedIn logo or the ‘Share’ button on this website. When you visit this website, the plugin establishes a direct connection between your browser and the LinkedIn server. LinkedIn receives the information that you have visited this website with your IP address. If you click the LinkedIn ‘Share-Button’ while logged into your LinkedIn account, you can link the contents of this website on your LinkedIn profile. This allows LinkedIn to associate your visit to this website with your user account. We would like to point out that we, as website operators, are not aware of the content of the transmitted data or its use by LinkedIn. Details on data collection (purpose, scope, further processing, use) as well as your rights and setting options can be found in LinkedIn’s data protection information. LinkedIn provides this information on the following page:

13\. Third-party services
-------------------------

We use the services of third parties for various functions of our website.

### 13.1 Easy Marketing GmbH

This is our technical service provider for our tracking system medialead: [https://easy-m.de/](https://easy-m.de/)

### 13.2. nitramIT GmbH

This is our technical service provider for abo-angebot.de: [https://www.nitramit.de/](https://www.nitramit.de/)

### 13.3 Salesforce

Our registration service allows visitors to our website to learn more about our company, download content and provide contact information and other demographic information. This information is stored on servers of our software partner Salesforce. They can be used by us to contact visitors to our website and to determine which services of our company are of interest to them. All information we collect is subject to this privacy policy. We use all collected information exclusively to optimize our marketing. Salesforce.com is a TRUSTe Privacy Seal Certified Licensee. For more information about salesforce.com’s handling of personal information, please see the complete privacy policy: [http://www.salesforce.com/de/company/full\_privacy.jsp](http://www.salesforce.com/de/company/full_privacy.jsp). Questions regarding the data protection declaration or the handling of personal data should be addressed here or by post to the following address: Salesforce.com Privacy; The Landmark @ One Market Street, Suite 300; San Francisco, CA 94105, USA.

### 13.4 Newsletter and mailchimp

Information on the newsletter and consents

With the following information we inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the registration, dispatch and statistical evaluation procedure and your rights of objection. By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt and the described procedures.

#### Contents of the newsletter

We will only send newsletters, e-mails and other electronic notifications containing advertising information (hereinafter “newsletters”) with the consent of the recipients or a legal permission. If the contents of a newsletter are specifically described within the scope of a registration, they are decisive for the consent of the users.

#### Double-Opt-In and logging

The registration for our newsletter takes place in a so-called double opt-in procedure. This means that after registration you will receive an e-mail asking you to confirm your registration. This confirmation is necessary so that no one can log in with other e-mail addresses.

Subscriptions to the newsletter are logged in order to be able to prove the registration process in accordance with legal requirements. This includes the storage of the login and confirmation time, as well as the IP address. Also, the changes of your data stored with MailChimp are logged.

#### Use of the “MailChimp” distribution service

The newsletter is sent via “MailChimp”, a newsletter distribution platform of the US provider Rocket Science Group, LLC, 675 Ponce De Leon Ave NE #5000, Atlanta, GA 30308, USA.

The e-mail addresses of our newsletter recipients, as well as their further data described in the context of these notes, are stored on the servers of MailChimp in the USA. MailChimp uses this information to send and evaluate the newsletter on our behalf. Furthermore, MailChimp can use this data according to its own information to optimize or improve its own services, e.g. to technically optimize the sending and presentation of the newsletter or for economic purposes, in order to determine from which countries, the recipients come. However, MailChimp does not use the data of our newsletter recipients to write them down or pass them on to third parties.

We trust in the reliability and IT and data security of MailChimp. MailChimp is certified under the US-EU data protection agreement “Privacy Shield” and thus commits itself to comply with EU data protection regulations. Furthermore, we have concluded a data processing agreement with MailChimp. This is a contract in which MailChimp undertakes to protect the data of our users, to process them on our behalf in accordance with their data protection regulations and in particular not to pass them on to third parties. The data protection regulations of MailChimp can be viewed here: [https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

#### Registration details

To subscribe to the newsletter, simply enter your e-mail address.

Optionally, we ask you to enter your first and last name. This information is only used to personalize the newsletter.

#### Statistical surveys and analyses

The newsletters contain a so-called “web-beacon”, i.e. a pixel-sized file that is retrieved from the MailChimp server when the newsletter is opened. Within the scope of this retrieval, technical information, such as information about the browser and your system, as well as your IP address and time of retrieval are initially collected. This information is used to technically improve the services based on the technical data or the target groups and their reading behavior based on their retrieval locations (which can be determined using the IP address) or access times.

The statistical surveys also include determining whether the newsletters are opened, when they are opened and which links are clicked. For technical reasons, this information can be assigned to the individual newsletter recipients. However, it is neither our endeavor, nor that of MailChimp, to observe individual users. The evaluations serve us much more to recognize the reading habits of our users and to adapt our contents to them or to send different contents according to the interests of our users.

#### Online access and data management

There are cases, in which we direct the newsletter recipients to the web pages of MailChimp. For example, our newsletters contain a link with which the newsletter recipients can call up the newsletters online (e.g. in case of display problems in the e-mail program). Furthermore, newsletter recipients can subsequently correct their data, e.g. the e-mail address. Likewise, the privacy policy of MailChimp is only available on their site.

In this context we point out that cookies are used on the websites of MailChimp and thus personal data are processed by MailChimp, its partners and service providers (e.g. Google Analytics). We have no influence on this data collection. Further information can be found in the privacy policy of MailChimp. In addition, we would like to draw your attention to the possibilities of objecting to the collection of data for advertising purposes on the websites [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) and [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) (for the European area).

#### Cancellation/Revocation

You can cancel the receipt of our newsletter at any time, i.e. revoke your consent. At the same time your consents to its dispatch via MailChimp and the statistical analyses expire. A separate cancellation of the dispatch via MailChimp or the statistical evaluation is unfortunately not possible.

You will find a link to cancel the newsletter at the end of each newsletter.

#### Legal basis Basic Data Protection Ordinance

In accordance with the provisions of the German Version of the General Data Protection Resolution (DSGVO) valid from 25 May 2018, we inform you that your consents to the sending of e-mail addresses are based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a, 7 DSGVO and § 7 para. 2 no. 3 and para. 3 UWG. The use of the shipping service provider MailChimp, carrying out statistical surveys and analyses as well as logging of the registration procedure, are based on our legitimate interests pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. We are interested in using a user-friendly and secure newsletter system that serves both our business interests and the expectations of users.

We would also like to point out that you can object to the future processing of your personal data at any time in accordance with the statutory provisions of Art. 21 DSGVO. The objection may be lodged in particular against processing for direct marketing purposes.

14\. Rights of the data subject
-------------------------------

### 14.1 Consent

The Reach Group GmbH uses double opt-in solutions: If the user agrees to the use of his data for the stated purposes, this consent is confirmed in a second step. In this way, The Reach Group ensures that no one other than the user enters the user data and releases it for use by The Reach Group GmbH. In this way, The Reach Group GmbH respects the user’s right to informational self-determination. The user can revoke the given consent at any time in whole or in part by the same means by which he has given the consent.

We will log your consent to the collection and storage of data or have the logging carried out by our partners. If required, we will inform you when and how you have given your consent.

We only collect the data we need to enable you to participate in a service or those for which you have given us your consent, e.g. by registering. If you do not give your consent, we ask for your understanding that you cannot participate in the respective service.

The Reach Group GmbH also collects, processes and uses personal data on behalf of contractual or cooperation partners (e.g. website operators, advertising customers, agencies), for example for the purpose of generating addresses for a newsletter subscription, product information, orders or similar.

If data is collected on behalf of The Reach Group GmbH, the cooperation partner is clearly identifiable at all times. In this case, the user can only assert his rights against the cooperation partner of The Reach Group GmbH. If The Reach Group GmbH collects, processes and uses data on behalf of cooperation partners, the cooperation partner is responsible for compliance with data protection regulations. In this case, The Reach Group GmbH does not vouch to the user for compliance with data protection regulations by its cooperation partners. No rights or obligations arise for The Reach Group GmbH from contracts or similar relationships that the user may enter into with a cooperation partner. The Reach Group GmbH also has no influence on these contracts, either directly or indirectly. In this case, The Reach Group GmbH is bound by its cooperation partner’s instructions.

It goes without saying that The Reach Group GmbH will only cooperate with partners who observe the data protection principles mentioned in this declaration in the same way as The Reach Group GmbH or at least guarantee the standard applicable under the EU General Data Protection Resolution.

### 14.2 Transfer of data

The Reach Group GmbH will pass on the data collected and stored with your consent to business partners and sponsors within the framework of contractual agreements, insofar as this is necessary in your interest, for example, in the case of a contest. Of course, our business partners and sponsors are requested to comply with the legal data protection regulations. We collect your data in the following cases:

*   Subscriptions to newsletters, reminders
*   Participation in contests, voting
*   Community membership, forums, chats
*   Participation in electronic payment procedures
*   Sending of further information

Depending on the situation, name, address, gender, date of birth, client id, telephone number, fax number, bank details, method of payment and e-mail address are collected and stored. In the case of electronic payment procedures, data may be collected and stored in accordance with the respective procedure.

All personal data collected by us, our partners, customers, third party service providers or subsidiaries, if applicable, is additionally centrally secured by The Reach Group GmbH and, if applicable, further processed or analyzed to create an anonymized profile if we have your consent.

We would like to expressly point out that we dissociate ourselves from the contents of the pages linked on this and all other pages of our Internet presence. We expressly point out that we have no influence on the contents of external homepages. Should the external sites contain violations of morality or laws, we will delete the links to these sites from our Internet presence immediately after becoming aware of these violations.

The Reach Group GmbH will not pass on any data to non-EU countries without your consent, unless this is expressly permitted by the DSGVO.

### 14.3 Right of information

You can obtain information about the data we have stored about you at any time. If required, please write to:

The Reach Group GmbH

Am Karlsbad 16

10785 Berlin

Germany

or send an e-mail to: [privacy@trg.de](mailto:privacy@trg.de)

The Reach Group GmbH or its cooperation partners grant the user the right to obtain information about the data stored about the user, to delete or block such data. These rights are to be asserted against The Reach Group GmbH if The Reach Group GmbH has collected, processed and used the user data; they are to be asserted against the cooperation partner if the latter has the user data collected, processed or used by The Reach Group GmbH.

You can contact our data protection officer at:

Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer

ePrivacy GmbH

Large bleaching 21

20354 Hamburg

### 14.4 Data security and protection

The Reach Group GmbH is legally obliged to take the technical and organizational measures necessary to guarantee the protection of personal data, i.e. in particular to protect this data from unauthorized access and processing. All data-processing programs and facilities are password-protected and work using state-of-the-art encryption techniques.

If The Reach Group GmbH uses external servers or service providers to store user data and, where applicable, profile information, The Reach Group GmbH ensures that they are bound by at least the same data protection standards as The Reach Group GmbH itself.

The employees of The Reach Group GmbH are committed to maintaining data secrecy and data protection. This obligation includes, among other things, that employees may only process and use personal data to the extent that this is necessary within the framework of contractual or contract-like relationships or the customer has consented to the use of his data for the respective purposes. Personal data that is no longer required for the fulfilment of contractual purposes by The Reach Group GmbH and/or for the processing and use of which The Reach Group no longer has (or no longer) consent will be destroyed in a way that excludes any misuse.

### 14.5 Right of objection

Furthermore, you may at any time revoke your consent to the collection and storage of your personal data by The Reach Group GmbH.

If required, please write to:

The Reach Group GmbH

Am Karlsbad 16

10785 Berlin

Germany

or send an e-mail to: [privacy@trg.de](mailto:privacy@trg.de)

Your data will be deleted under the following conditions:

You have no outstanding payment obligations;

The Reach Group GmbH does not consider it absolutely necessary to keep this data for any pending legal dispute;

There is another legal obligation to keep your information.

If you have any questions about data protection, please contact us at: privacy@reachgroup.com

### Status of this data protection declaration

16.10.2019

We reserve the right to change this data protection declaration at any time with effect for the future.
